<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>network on marcfargas.com</title><link>https://www.marcfargas.com/tags/network/</link><description>Recent content in network on marcfargas.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 | Follow on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/telenieko" target="_blank">Twitter&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="https://github.com/mgjohansen/hucore.git" target="_blank">Hucore theme&lt;/a> &amp; &lt;a href="http://gohugo.io" target="_blank">Hugo&lt;/a> ♥</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 21:43:57 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.marcfargas.com/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enable Wireless networks in Debian Initramfs</title><link>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/2017/enable-wireless-debian-initramfs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 21:43:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/2017/enable-wireless-debian-initramfs/</guid><description>Initramfs is a very tiny environment in which your Linux system boots in order to do a lot of initialisation magic before loading your system. The most common use case is to mount the root filesystem, like when it’s encrypted and you need to type a passphrase to mount it. Or if fsck needs to run on an unclean root filesystem. Basically anything that goes before mounting the root filesystem and, after that, before launching INIT (you can read more in the Debian Wiki).</description></item><item><title>Moved to Google Apps</title><link>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/moved-to-google-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 19:47:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/moved-to-google-apps/</guid><description>I started to get tired of managing my own exim+spamassassin+clamav+dovecot only to serve my domain, so I dediced to give Google Apps a try.
The move was fairly easy, simply register and change MX records ;) (and use imapsync to copy mail). I guess I didn&amp;rsquo;t loose anything but If you sent me a mail in the last two weeks and I haven&amp;rsquo;t answered, please resend.
The only downside, I hoped google would have some &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; way to move my google account from *@gmail.</description></item><item><title>Ip Tunnel Over Ssh With Tun</title><link>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/ip-tunnel-over-ssh-with-tun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 10:14:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/ip-tunnel-over-ssh-with-tun/</guid><description>Today I had some connection problems in one of our offices, so I needed to connect in some alternative way. A good moment for experimenting&amp;hellip; The alternative connection was my laptop acting as a router connected with my mobile phone via bluetooth.
The problem&amp;rsquo;s come with the VPN connections, IPSec is nice, but you can hate it on lots of things&amp;hellip; i.e. all tunnels are setup using static ip addresses so in order to use the alternate connection (dynamic IP) I need to change the ipsec config of the other offices.</description></item><item><title>Outgoing connections from Linux not working</title><link>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/outgoing-connections-from-linux-not-working/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2008 13:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.marcfargas.com/posts/outgoing-connections-from-linux-not-working/</guid><description>A friend of mine has a nice MythTV box on his bedroom. Suddently the box decided to not open outgoing connections anymore&amp;hellip; I say outgoing because I could still connect to it from my home.
I could not find out what was last changed, maybe an aptitude upgrade or did he change ISP?
After some time looking around the only thing I could find out was a small difference between a SYN packet send from a remote place and the SYN packets send by the broken system:</description></item></channel></rss>